when we talk about processor performance
we typically talk about its speed how
many instructions per second can it
finish but we also have to consider its
fabrication cost and the power
consumption it will have lower
fabrication costs allow us to put
processors that are more powerful into
devices that cannot be expensive like
refrigerators and watches and all sorts
of other things low power consumption is
important not only because of the cost
of electricity but also because it
translates into longer battery life and
smaller form factors for things like
cell phones so what we really want is
that the speed of a processor doubles
over something like two years that the
cost of this twice as fast processor
stays about the same and that the power
consumption of this twice as fast
processor stays about the same as before
but we don't have to use technology
improvement to get this we can get
instead a smaller improvement in speed
let's say 1.1 X 4 about half the cost as
the original processor and let's say
about half the power consumption of the
original processor which one of these do
you want well it depends what kind of
computer you're building so one of the
jobs of computer architects is really to
figure out given that the technology can
provide either this or this or something
in between them actually there are many
more options which one do I really want
for a specific type of computer